# 陕西 西安
Xi’an, Shanxi
# 色香俱全
Full of flavor and fragment
# 走在回民街的巷子里
Walking in the alley of khui khui street
# 正好遇见大叔在这个地方熬卤汁
Just met uncle oiling gravy in this place
# 看来今天的午饭有着落了 吃一份卤汁凉粉
It’s our today’s lunch, eat a bean jelly with gravy
# 来吃卤汁凉粉的时候
When we are ready to eat a bean jelly with gravy
# 一人给一个碗 还给了我们一点馍
We have an empty bowl and a steamed bun
# 掰成黄豆粒大小 我每次掰 都感觉掰大了
We need breaking it into the size of soybeans, but i think i breaking it into bigger pieces every time
# 这个（掰馍的大小）是羊肉泡馍的馍
The size of breaking steamed bun are same as lamb paomo
# 掰这么大就行 再掰大一点
Breaking into size like this, a little bigger
# 掰了三分钟 掰好了
It took me 3 minutes to finish it
# 叔 帮我弄一下吧
Uncle, help me please
# 可以
sure
# 我知道 你吃辣椒不吃
I know, do you want spicy pepper?
# 都吃
Im fine
# 好来
okay
# 要加黑白蛋（黑色是松花蛋 白色是煮鸡蛋）
Black or white egg?(black egg is century egg, white egg is boiled egg)
# 要吃美食届的泥石流
You have to try “debris flow” in Gastronomy
# 是
What’s that?
# 这是好多朋友给我们家起的
That’s how our customers call us
# 一种是黑暗料理
First is wicked cuisine
# 一种是泥石流
And “debris  flow”
# 因为要吃的时候 （发出这种声音）
Because it sounds like debris flow
# 像泥石流的声音
When they eat it
# 加蒜蓉
Add mashed garlic
# 加芥末
Add black mustard seed
# 再加一个溏心的松花蛋
Add an century egg with soft yolk
# 哇 好重的芥末味
Wow, pretty strong flavor of black mustard seed
# 有时候呛的我眼睛都睁不开
Sometimes I can’t even open my eyes
# 好 谢谢
Okay, thank you
# 顺着边刨着吃
Eat along the side
# 好的 好的 好的
okay
# 走吧
Let’s go
# 这个就是号称 西安美食届的黑暗料理
This is called wicked cuisine of Xi’an Gastronomy
# 不过看颜色还挺好看的 不知道味道怎么样
The color are not bad, i don’t know how it taste
# 这里面就是 下面是馍 上面是凉粉
Steamed bun at bottom in the bowl and bean jelly on it
# 浇了卤汁 辣子 放了溏心的松花蛋和白蛋
With topping of gravy, spicy pepper, both century egg and boiled egg with soft yolk
# 叔说 得顺着碗沿吃 不能翻
Uncle said we should eat along the side of the bowl, not just mixed it up
# 吃的时候 还有点不知所措呢
I don’t know about it before when i eat it
# 不仅芥末汁辣眼睛 可能我吃的样子也有点辣眼睛
Not just black mustard seed make my eyes sting,
# 有点辣
A little spicy
# 蛋就直接这么吃吗
Just eat them straightly
# 其实我感觉 卤汁凉粉就是不同食材的搭配
Actually i think bean jelly with gravy is mixed with different ingredients
# 溏心的松花蛋 白蛋
Century egg and boiled egg both with soft yolk
# 热的卤子 凉粉
Hot gravy and bean jelly
# 还有呢 就是加了辣子和蒜汁的混合味道
And the mixed of spicy pepper and garlic sauce taste
# 麻酱味很浓郁
And strong flavor of sesame sauce
# 吃着吃着还有些小惊喜 比如说馍的嚼劲
The texture of steamed buns surprised me
# 这一碗就是（调料）该加的都加了
All mixed of condiments in the bowl of bean jelly
# 味道呢 酸甜苦辣咸
With flavors of sweetness, sourness, bitter, spicy and salty
# 吃得惯的 可能觉得很美味
People who used with it might think it’s delicious
# 吃不惯的 也不要勉强自己
Don’t force yourself to do it if you’re not used to it
# 你看 每一个进来的人 来到之后就会被发一个碗
Look, everyone who come in will get an empty bowl
# 大家就开始在这个地方掰馍
Everyone start breaking their steamed buns in this place
# 感觉吃个饭 都很有仪式感
it feels a sense of ritual when they gonna eat
# 能吃惯吗
Can you get used to it?
# 大部分人 基本上都能吃惯
mostly
# 有一小部分人 他就感觉有芝麻酱 蒜蓉 芥末
A few people don’t like sesame sauce, garlic sauce, and black mustard seed
# 他平时又不吃这个
He not eat this usually
# 吃不了重口的
Can not eat salty food
# 有的人 一吃不得了 特别香
Someone like this
# 适合他那个口味
It fit his food behavior
# 隔三差五地慢慢 慢慢来
He start to come here often
# 他还把其他的朋友带来
And he bring his friends as well
# 有的外地朋友来了之后 他真的吃不惯
After some friends who from other city came and really couldn’t get used to it
# 因为这个调料 佐料是比较偏重的
Because the condiments in pretty strong flavors
# 西安人 本身吃这个调料 比如说羊肉泡馍 卤汁凉粉
People who from Xi’an used to
# 这都是比较重的一个口味
Pretty strong flavor
# 外地人来了以后 接受不了 一下子接受不了
People who from other city not used at first time
# 吃过几次的时候 慢慢慢慢就吃习惯了
After eating it a few times, they gradually get used to it
# 这一习惯 不得了
It never stop after they get used to it
# 来了
here
# 你看 这都是我们家的老粉丝
Look, they all are our fans
# 老顾客了 老吃家了
Old customers, and old foodies
# 一大早呢吃了大家传说当中的 黑暗料理
Eat the “wicked cuisine” people called at the morning
# 其实并没有想象当中的那么 难以接受
Actually it’s not what i thought it hard to acceptable
# 好了 今天的视频就到这儿 拜拜
Okay, today’s video is done. Bye.